MURPHY VAUGHN

Nashville, TN 37207

Phone: 615.457.0185 | **Email:** vaughnmurphy89@gmail.com **LinkedIn:** https://linkedin.com/in/murphy-vaughn-a256881a4

GitHub: https://github.com/proflonghair07

Portfolio: https://proflonghair07.github.io/Murphy_Vaughn_Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer who specializes in front-end development. Makes applications with a clean and visually pleasing design. Has a strong work ethic derived from a long career in restaurant management. A strong ability to manage multiple responsibilities, work under stressful conditions, and streamline efficiency to meet time sensitive deadlines. Possesses skills with many technologies and frameworks, but eager, and motivated to expand and refine skill set.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Libraries: React.js, jQuery, Express.js, Node.js, Mongoose

CSS Frameworks: Bootstrap, Bulma

Database Management Systems: MySQL, MongoDB

PROJECTS

Toddler Shopper — A mock shopping application that allows children to pretend shop Deployed Site - https://mighty-woodland-98663.herokuapp.com/

Github Repository - https://github.com/proflonghair07/Toddler Shopper Twelve

- **Project Description** A mock shopping application that allows children to pretend shop with an interface that is similar to Amazon, but has a more kid friendly design, and prevents the user from seeing inappropriate material. This application is built as a MERN stack and has user authentication. It utilizes MongoDB to save the user's cart and login credentials. It is styled using the Bulma CSS framework.
- **Contributions** Executed all of the frameworking in React.js. Styled the pages using the Bulma CSS framework. Applied all animations using Anime.js and Animate.css.
- **Technologies Used** MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, Bulma, Howler.js, React.js, Anime.js, Animate.css, and Node.js.

Trivia App — Randomly Generated Multiple Choice Trivia Quiz Deployed Site - https://serene-inlet-83004.herokuapp.com/

Github Repository - https://github.com/proflonghair07/Project_2

- **Project Description** A trivia application that pulls it's questions from the OpenTDB API. Allows the user to sign up via email and join or create a team. The Application stores the user's scores and averages team scores via a MySQL database.
- **Contributions** Responsible for all html templating and css styling. Developed the quiz portion of the app with vanilla Javascript and connected it to the OpenTDB api.
- Technologies Used Express.js, Handlebars.js, Node.js, Velocity, Bootstrap, MYSQL, Sequelize, and Node.js.

Employee Directory — An employee directory built with React.js

Deployed Site - https://proflonghair07.github.io/Employee_Directory/

Github Repository - https://github.com/proflonghair07/Employee_Directory

- Project Description An employee directory built with React.js. It allows the user to search for employees by their first name, sort employees by first name, and sort employees by age.
- **Contributions** Wrote all front-end Javascript and did all styling utilizing the Bootstrap CSS framework.
- Technologies Used React.js, Bootstrap, Axios, and Node.js.

Recipe App — Recipe App That Finds Recipes Based On User Input

Deployed Site - https://proflonghair07.github.io/Recipe_Finder/

Github Repository - https://github.com/proflonghair07/Recipe Finder

- Project Description A recipe finding app that utilizes the Spoonacular api. Allows
 users to search for recipes by keywords, and filter the results to be either vegan,
 gluten-free, neither, or both.
- Contributions Created all html and css. Used the bulma framework for styling.
 Wrote all Javascript using jQuery.
- Technologies Used Bulma, Day.js, Spoonacular api, and jQuery.

EXPERIENCE

Executive Chef Silo

May 2018 – March 2020 Nashville, TN

- Managed and staffed a Kitchen of 15 employees.
- Wrote and maintained a seasonal menu.
- Established and maintained positive relations with a diverse variety of vendors
- Consistently maintained a food cost of 27 percent or lower.

• Led dinner and brunch services in high stress conditions at a consistent and high level of efficiency.

Sous Chef

July 2016 – September 2017

Nashville, TN

Cochon Butcher

- Managed and staffed a Kitchen of 12 employees.
- Monitored food/labor costs, and recognized areas for improvement
- Standardized recipes for consistent reproduction.
- Assisted executive chef in ordering and the inventory of products...

Sous Chef Butchertown Hall

February 2015 – September 2015

Nashville, TN

- Implemented systems to control spoilage and preserve foods.
- Supervised daily lunch operations, while managing a prep team.
- Acted as head chef in the executive chef's absence.
- Developed and implemented procedures for operation in a new restaurant.
- Trained and supervised new employees.

EDUCATION

Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tn — *Full Stack Bootcamp Certificate* April 2020 - October 2020

Meridian High School, Meridian, Ms — *Diploma*Class of 2007